{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Enterprise rollout",
      "pos": [
        11,
        29
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise rollout",
      "pos": [
        180,
        198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the enterprise rollout phase, you will plan and execute your broad rollout strategy, inclusive of communications, training and support activities.",
      "pos": [
        199,
        352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Why is this important?",
      "pos": [
        357,
        379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you've evaluated your pilot and determined you're ready for your broad rollout, you need to consider the optimal approach for enabling your broad user base.",
      "pos": [
        380,
        541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A phased approach is strongly encouraged, whether to a select number of users per week, or by location or workload.",
      "pos": [
        542,
        657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This approach enables you to monitor progress, to make adjustments to your rollout schedule if issues arise, and helps ensure a positive first experience for your end-users.",
      "pos": [
        658,
        831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Begin by reviewing the discovery questions to the left, to help scope and define your rollout phase.",
      "pos": [
        832,
        932
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discovery questions",
      "pos": [
        937,
        956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discuss these questions with your project team to help scope your project details, uncover potential risks, and define actionable tasks which can be documented in the  Rollout Planning Guide and Project Plan.",
      "pos": [
        957,
        1165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How will you rollout to your end-users?",
      "pos": [
        1171,
        1210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(ex: Phased by location, by workload, etc.)",
      "pos": [
        1211,
        1254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How does your organization handle broad communications?",
      "pos": [
        1260,
        1315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How will you monitor and report out on the success of the above-defined delivery channels?",
      "pos": [
        1321,
        1411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Who will be your Champs?",
      "pos": [
        1417,
        1441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What groups may need targeted messaging,  and what is your plan to communicate with them?",
      "pos": [
        1447,
        1536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do you typically train your end-users?",
      "pos": [
        1542,
        1584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What training approaches will you use?",
      "pos": [
        1585,
        1623
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do users know where to go for answers to keep from weighing down the support organization?",
      "pos": [
        1629,
        1719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Focus area goals",
      "pos": [
        1724,
        1740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Review this section for guidance on focus-area activities for this stated phase of your rollout.",
      "pos": [
        1741,
        1837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Planning",
      "pos": [
        1843,
        1851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key to planning an effective rollout is flexibility.",
      "pos": [
        1852,
        1908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Decide how you will rollout (i.e.",
      "pos": [
        1909,
        1942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "phased by department, by location, or all at once).",
      "pos": [
        1943,
        1994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identify targeted groups for training and communications.",
      "pos": [
        1995,
        2052
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enlist your entire project team to ensure each department is ready to support the influx of users.",
      "pos": [
        2053,
        2151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor your progress and adjust your plan based on user reception and feedback.",
      "pos": [
        2152,
        2232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Develop a communication plan to inform users about the upcoming changes and any actions required of them.Administrators, help desk personnel and corporate communications professionals should develop this communication plan.",
      "pos": [
        2234,
        2457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Help desk",
      "pos": [
        2463,
        2472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your help desk is where new users will go with questions.",
      "pos": [
        2473,
        2530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure your support team is well-prepared with information about  changes such as new policies and apps, and troubleshooting tips for new users.",
      "pos": [
        2531,
        2676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Awareness",
      "pos": [
        2682,
        2691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inform, involve, and inspire your users, and it will pay dividends in the long-term including positive end-user experience, reduced help desk incidents, viral adoption, and increased usage.",
      "pos": [
        2692,
        2881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use multiple channels in your awareness campaign; you'll get a stronger response if you say the same thing in different media.",
      "pos": [
        2882,
        3008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Training",
      "pos": [
        3014,
        3022
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instilling end-user confidence is a key component in supporting long term usage and adoption.",
      "pos": [
        3023,
        3116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "End-user training can take many forms, from instructor-led sessions to self-study resources.",
      "pos": [
        3117,
        3209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Incorporate feedback from Pilot participants when developing end-user learning materials.",
      "pos": [
        3210,
        3299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User training decreases end-user ramp up time and minimizes calls to your help desk.",
      "pos": [
        3300,
        3384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Helping users map their current behavior to the required new behavior is an important part of your training program.",
      "pos": [
        3385,
        3501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to customize training to match the workloads you have deployed.",
      "pos": [
        3502,
        3573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations",
      "pos": [
        3579,
        3589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to document key lessons including what went well, and areas for improvement, during your Enterprise Rollout phase.",
      "pos": [
        3590,
        3712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leverage this data to plan for successful long-term operations.",
      "pos": [
        3713,
        3776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get started checklist",
      "pos": [
        3781,
        3802
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3803,
        3884
      ],
      "content": "Here is a list of steps to get you started with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enterprise rollout<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> phase."
    },
    {
      "content": "Establish optimal approach for broad rollout (by workload, location, etc.) and plan accordingly.",
      "pos": [
        3890,
        3986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Include timeline, measurement and goal tracking, reporting.",
      "pos": [
        3992,
        4051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identify groups who may require targeted communications and training.",
      "pos": [
        4057,
        4126
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4132,
        4249
      ],
      "content": "Customize email communications, update intranet site\nIdentify ongoing owner for communications/resource updating.",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "    "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Customize email communications, update intranet site",
          "pos": [
            0,
            52
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Identify ongoing owner for communications/resource updating.",
          "pos": [
            53,
            113
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outline which training methods you will use.",
      "pos": [
        4255,
        4299
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4305,
        4515
      ],
      "content": "Create a Getting Started checklist and enrollment guide for end-users.\nUse the [Microsoft Intune Enrollment Instructions](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=46398) as a starting point.",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "    "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Create a Getting Started checklist and enrollment guide for end-users.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            70
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Intune Enrollment Instructions<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=46398)</ept> as a starting point.",
          "pos": [
            71,
            206
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Define a process for updating training materials, as needed",
      "pos": [
        4521,
        4580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Implement broad rollout plan.",
      "pos": [
        4586,
        4615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Common challenges",
      "pos": [
        4620,
        4637
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4638,
        4723
      ],
      "content": "Here are some  challenges that you may encounter in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enterprise rollout<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> phase."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4729,
        4793
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Challenge:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Emails were sent, but adoption is not picking up."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mitigation:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Understand that users may get hundreds, if not thousands of emails a day.",
      "pos": [
        4799,
        4888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To help ensure your message is heard: (1) have an executive sponsor send out the initial messaging, (2) keep your email short and focus on the value-prop, (3) have a clear call-to-action, and (4) use several different awareness generating tactics- put up posters in cafeterias letting users know to check their inbox, for example.",
      "pos": [
        4889,
        5219
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5225,
        5308
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Challenge:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Users are resistant to change and push back on using new technology."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5314,
        5471
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mitigation:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>Use the positive experiences of your pilot users to promote the use of devices managed by <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[wit_nextref](../Token/wit_nextref_md.md)]</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5477,
        5564
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Challenge:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Users feel if they have to be trained, the solution must be hard to use."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mitigation:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Everyone learns at a different pace.",
      "pos": [
        5570,
        5622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some pick up new technology without any instruction, while others require some guidance or hand-holding.",
      "pos": [
        5623,
        5727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Training can offer tips for ensuring users are getting the most out of the solution, and can be broken out into smaller brown bags or by department to not overwhelm users or appear too detailed.",
      "pos": [
        5728,
        5922
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Position training as a value-add and offer segmented training/brown bags.",
      "pos": [
        5923,
        5996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To maximize user learning and adoption, incorporate a variety of training methods into your plan.",
      "pos": [
        5997,
        6094
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "---\ntitle: Enterprise rollout\nms.custom: na\nms.reviewer: na\nms.suite: na\nms.tgt_pltfrm: na\nms.topic: article\nms.assetid: d894708e-7071-44f5-aa3b-af5aef02fb98\nauthor: Nbigman\n---\n# Enterprise rollout\nDuring the enterprise rollout phase, you will plan and execute your broad rollout strategy, inclusive of communications, training and support activities.\n\n## Why is this important?\nOnce you've evaluated your pilot and determined you're ready for your broad rollout, you need to consider the optimal approach for enabling your broad user base. A phased approach is strongly encouraged, whether to a select number of users per week, or by location or workload. This approach enables you to monitor progress, to make adjustments to your rollout schedule if issues arise, and helps ensure a positive first experience for your end-users.\nBegin by reviewing the discovery questions to the left, to help scope and define your rollout phase.\n\n## Discovery questions\nDiscuss these questions with your project team to help scope your project details, uncover potential risks, and define actionable tasks which can be documented in the  Rollout Planning Guide and Project Plan.\n\n-   How will you rollout to your end-users? (ex: Phased by location, by workload, etc.)\n\n-   How does your organization handle broad communications?\n\n-   How will you monitor and report out on the success of the above-defined delivery channels?\n\n-   Who will be your Champs?\n\n-   What groups may need targeted messaging,  and what is your plan to communicate with them?\n\n-   How do you typically train your end-users? What training approaches will you use?\n\n-   Do users know where to go for answers to keep from weighing down the support organization?\n\n## Focus area goals\nReview this section for guidance on focus-area activities for this stated phase of your rollout.\n\n### Planning\nThe key to planning an effective rollout is flexibility. Decide how you will rollout (i.e. phased by department, by location, or all at once). Identify targeted groups for training and communications. Enlist your entire project team to ensure each department is ready to support the influx of users. Monitor your progress and adjust your plan based on user reception and feedback.\n\nDevelop a communication plan to inform users about the upcoming changes and any actions required of them.Administrators, help desk personnel and corporate communications professionals should develop this communication plan.\n\n### Help desk\nYour help desk is where new users will go with questions. Be sure your support team is well-prepared with information about  changes such as new policies and apps, and troubleshooting tips for new users.\n\n### Awareness\nInform, involve, and inspire your users, and it will pay dividends in the long-term including positive end-user experience, reduced help desk incidents, viral adoption, and increased usage. Use multiple channels in your awareness campaign; you'll get a stronger response if you say the same thing in different media.\n\n### Training\nInstilling end-user confidence is a key component in supporting long term usage and adoption. End-user training can take many forms, from instructor-led sessions to self-study resources. Incorporate feedback from Pilot participants when developing end-user learning materials. User training decreases end-user ramp up time and minimizes calls to your help desk. Helping users map their current behavior to the required new behavior is an important part of your training program. Be sure to customize training to match the workloads you have deployed.\n\n### Operations\nBe sure to document key lessons including what went well, and areas for improvement, during your Enterprise Rollout phase. Leverage this data to plan for successful long-term operations.\n\n## Get started checklist\nHere is a list of steps to get you started with the **Enterprise rollout** phase.\n\n-   Establish optimal approach for broad rollout (by workload, location, etc.) and plan accordingly.\n\n-   Include timeline, measurement and goal tracking, reporting.\n\n-   Identify groups who may require targeted communications and training.\n\n-   Customize email communications, update intranet site\n    Identify ongoing owner for communications/resource updating.\n\n-   Outline which training methods you will use.\n\n-   Create a Getting Started checklist and enrollment guide for end-users.\n    Use the [Microsoft Intune Enrollment Instructions](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=46398) as a starting point.\n\n-   Define a process for updating training materials, as needed\n\n-   Implement broad rollout plan.\n\n## Common challenges\nHere are some  challenges that you may encounter in the **Enterprise rollout** phase.\n\n-   **Challenge:** Emails were sent, but adoption is not picking up.\n\n    **Mitigation:** Understand that users may get hundreds, if not thousands of emails a day. To help ensure your message is heard: (1) have an executive sponsor send out the initial messaging, (2) keep your email short and focus on the value-prop, (3) have a clear call-to-action, and (4) use several different awareness generating tactics- put up posters in cafeterias letting users know to check their inbox, for example.\n\n-   **Challenge:** Users are resistant to change and push back on using new technology.\n\n    **Mitigation:**Use the positive experiences of your pilot users to promote the use of devices managed by [!INCLUDE[wit_nextref](../Token/wit_nextref_md.md)].\n\n-   **Challenge:** Users feel if they have to be trained, the solution must be hard to use.\n\n    **Mitigation:** Everyone learns at a different pace. Some pick up new technology without any instruction, while others require some guidance or hand-holding. Training can offer tips for ensuring users are getting the most out of the solution, and can be broken out into smaller brown bags or by department to not overwhelm users or appear too detailed. Position training as a value-add and offer segmented training/brown bags. To maximize user learning and adoption, incorporate a variety of training methods into your plan.\n\n"
}