{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "RASK core components",
      "pos": [
        11,
        31
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RASK core components",
      "pos": [
        207,
        227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RASK is organized into 3 core components: Rollout Phases, Readiness Focus Areas, and the Deployment Readiness Report.",
      "pos": [
        228,
        345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Together, these components create a framework designed for maximum flexibility and easy customization to reflect the unique characteristics of your organization and be relevant to deployments of almost any size or complexity.",
      "pos": [
        347,
        572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This adaptable framework allows for easy navigation between phases to support good visibility of what's ahead or what you may have missed if you've discovered RASK after your deployment is already underway.",
      "pos": [
        573,
        779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RASK rollout phases",
      "pos": [
        784,
        803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Organized into five phases, Project Scope, Proof of Concept, Pilot, Enterprise rollout, and Run State, RASK loosely maps to the typical phases of a core technical deployment.",
      "pos": [
        804,
        978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While your organization may use different terminology, the associated Phase definitions provide an easy mechanism to quickly identify which best represents your organization's current deployment state.",
      "pos": [
        979,
        1180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Project scope",
      "pos": [
        1187,
        1200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Understand goals, deployment, and rollout strategy.",
      "pos": [
        1201,
        1252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Proof of concept",
      "pos": [
        1259,
        1275
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test technical deployment &amp;amp; network architecture.",
      "pos": [
        1276,
        1329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pilot",
      "pos": [
        1336,
        1341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With a sample of enrolled devices, validate scenarios, resources, and rollout plans with user in preparation for broad rollout.",
      "pos": [
        1342,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise rollout",
      "pos": [
        1476,
        1494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Launch across all departments and user groups.",
      "pos": [
        1495,
        1541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run state",
      "pos": [
        1548,
        1557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations plan for all key phases/focus areas, increase user-adoption.",
      "pos": [
        1558,
        1629
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "---\ntitle: RASK core components\nms.custom: na\nms.reviewer: na\nms.suite: na\nms.tgt_pltfrm: na\nms.topic: article\nms.assetid: 1dcef89a-72d9-4634-8058-fd5d58a19ffd\nauthor: Nbigman\nrobots: noindex,nofollow\n---\n# RASK core components\nRASK is organized into 3 core components: Rollout Phases, Readiness Focus Areas, and the Deployment Readiness Report.  Together, these components create a framework designed for maximum flexibility and easy customization to reflect the unique characteristics of your organization and be relevant to deployments of almost any size or complexity. This adaptable framework allows for easy navigation between phases to support good visibility of what's ahead or what you may have missed if you've discovered RASK after your deployment is already underway.\n\n## RASK rollout phases\nOrganized into five phases, Project Scope, Proof of Concept, Pilot, Enterprise rollout, and Run State, RASK loosely maps to the typical phases of a core technical deployment. While your organization may use different terminology, the associated Phase definitions provide an easy mechanism to quickly identify which best represents your organization's current deployment state.\n\n#### Project scope\nUnderstand goals, deployment, and rollout strategy.\n\n#### Proof of concept\nTest technical deployment &amp; network architecture.\n\n#### Pilot\nWith a sample of enrolled devices, validate scenarios, resources, and rollout plans with user in preparation for broad rollout.\n\n#### Enterprise rollout\nLaunch across all departments and user groups.\n\n#### Run state\nOperations plan for all key phases/focus areas, increase user-adoption.\n\n"
}